CSLU

Computer Science

http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com

Personal Statement

I am presently a graduate student at Oregon Health and Sciences University. After completing my BS at Western Washington University, and my 4 years industry expirience, I have developed strong interests in cryptography, probabilistic programming, and lanquages. I am a very quick study, as I have adopted a new programming language or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has granted me strong communication skills, and solid background.

Language Experience :

* Python Figaro Julia ETEX Scala Ada С

Education ____

Oregon Health Science University

Non-Matriculated (Masters)

2016 - present

Courses :

Analysis of Sequences Statistical Methods Univariate Statistical Analysis Digital Signal Processing

Western Washington University

Computer Science BS Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

Core Coursework :

Unix Software Development Formal Languages/Automata Windows Software Development Programming Languages Operating Systems Concurrent Programming Analysis/Design of Algorithms Computer Organization I/II Linear/Non-Linear Data Structures Object-Oriented Programming in C++

Elective Coursework :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Computer Architecture Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Number Theory Artificial Intelligence Elementary Real Analysis Natural Language Processing Ordinary Differential Equations Functional Programming Linear Algebra I/II Computer Graphics Abstract Algebra

Honors and Related Activities

Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Meritorious Winner) - Top 10% - Feb. 2012 Pacific Rim Regional Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition (Fourth Place) - March 2012 Comap Mathematical Modeling Competition (Honorable Mention) - Top 30% - Feb. 2011

Neato Projects _____

Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Course Dating a Band - Lyrics Release Date Classifier Probabilistic-Program Profiler and Evaluator Harness Probabilistic WiFi Geolocation Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System

sklearn, scipy, PonyORM, Python javascript, Python SLURM, PonyORM, Python Figaro, Scala, Javascript Hadoop, Python Erlang, Sagemath R, Perl Ada

Work Experience

Independent

- Contractor/Consultant

C&W Energy

Nov. 2015 - present

Authored educational material on light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Light classification engine, custom photo image processing tools, and mathematical models Developed a memoizing database-interface for caching computationally expensive operations

ComScore June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis

PDXCodeGuild June 2016

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable workflow for remote company Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++

Galois Inc. - Research Engineer

April 2014 - Dec 2015

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track
Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs
Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers
Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

 ${\tt EMC}^2$ Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director/Mentor Sept. 2009 - March 2012

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Ran student/faculty meetings to project future program responsibilities
Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Languages Used: Ada, C++, Scheme, R